She will die young.
Morirá joven.
Before Lord Habaek comes back and takes the throne,
Antes de que el Sr. Habaek asuma el trono,
she will die.
va a morir.
I shall grace you with my blessing,
Te daré mi bendición,
so wake up already.
así que despierta.
You...
Ahora…
You now belong to the gods
Ahora me perteneces.
Accept your fate, or you'll go through everything.
Acepta tu destino o sufrirás.
How do you feel now?
¿Cómo te sientes?
Don't you feel like something in your heart is smacking your head?
¿No sientes que tu corazón te quiere decir algo?
You should feel honored...
Deberías sentirte honrada por recibir el beso de un dios.
-What are you doing? -You crazy jerk!
- ¿Qué haces? - ¡Loco idiota!
I knew it. It didn't wake her.
Lo sabía. No la despertó.
See? I told you she'd be mad.
¿Ves? Te dije que se enojaría.
Go fix this.
Arregla esto.
Are you scared?
¿Tienes miedo?
Fine.
Bien.
I'll do it for you just this once.
Lo haré por ti solo esta vez.
No way.
De ninguna manera.
You've been saying that a lot since you arrived here.
Has dicho eso muchas veces desde que llegamos aquí.
Who do you think you are talking to?
¿Con quién crees que estás hablando?
You shouldn't kiss a woman like that out of nowhere.
No debería besar a una mujer así de la nada.
What are you talking about?
¿De qué hablas?
It didn't wake her. If you go now, she'll slap you in the face.
No despertó. Si va, lo abofeteará.
My gosh.
Dios mío.
I must have been out of my mind.
Debo haber enloquecido.
I must have gone crazy.
Debo haberme vuelto loca.
Why did I close my eyes?
¿Por qué cerré los ojos?
I have to find a logical reason for closing my eyes.
Debo encontrar una razón para haberlo hecho.
Right. To avoid trauma...
Cierto, para evitar el trauma.
To avoid trauma,
Sí, para evitar un trauma.
I have to find a reason.
Debo encontrar una razón.
Face it and overcome.
Enfréntalo y supéralo.
Hey, you. Servant.
Oye, sirvienta.
No. Don't do it.
No, no lo hagas.
No!
¡No!
Don't you feel like something in your heart is smacking your head?
¿No sientes que tu corazón
-Absolutely not. -I'm pretty sure I'm right.
- No. - Sé que tengo razón.
You're wrong.
Te equivocas.
Stay away!
¡Vete!
You shouldn't kiss a woman like that out of nowhere.
No debería besar a una mujer así de la nada.
If you go now, she'll slap you in the face.
Si va ahora, le dará una bofetada.
She must be very stupid to not realize that she was blessed.
Debe ser muy tonta para no notar que fue bendecida.
I'm hungry.
Tengo hambre.
I'm very hungry.
Tengo mucha hambre.
I've had enough of stupid servants.
Ya me hartaron los sirvientes tontos.
No, you're wrong about this.
No, te equivocas.
She'll be awakened and she'll come and find me.
Ya despertará y vendrá a buscarme.
It's nothing.
No fue nada.
It's because the world has changed.
Es porque el mundo cambió.
Stupid Sang-yu didn't even call me to wake me up.
Sang-yu no llamó para despertarme.
My stomach...
Mi estómago…
It's Sunday. You're probably swearing at me, aren't you?
Es domingo. Seguro me estás insultando, ¿no?
It's Sunday. You're probably--
Es domingo. Seguro…
Right, it's Sunday.
Cierto, es domingo.
You're probably back in bed, aren't you? Get up.
¿Te acostaste de nuevo? Levántate.
-You're in bed again. Get up now. -Enough.
- Levántate. - Suficiente.
Go exercise.
Ve a hacer ejercicio.
Stop it already.
Ya para.
Get photosynthesized.
Ve a tomar sol. La vitamina D es importante para las mujeres.
Strong thighs will help you avoid getting diabetes when you are old.
Tener muslos fuertes ayuda a prevenir diabetes.
Strong thighs will help you avoid--
Tener muslos fuertes…
Dear God! I'd rather kill Yu Sang-yu and go to hell.
Prefiero matar a Yu Sang-yu e irme al infierno.
Why are there so many humans today?
¿Por qué hay tantos humanos hoy?
Move. You're blocking my way.
Quítate del camino.
It's called a bicycle. It's a form of transportation for humans.
Es una bicicleta, un medio de transporte.
A cycle? Why are there only two wheels?
¿Bicicleta? ¿Por qué tiene solo dos ruedas?
How can they ride it and not fall?
¿Cómo es que no se caen?
That's because...
Es porque…
Do you want to see other wheels?
¿Quiere ver otras ruedas?
Isn't it so cool?
¿No es genial?
Not really.
En realidad no.
Not all things with four wheels are equally fun.
No todo lo que tiene cuatro ruedas es divertido.
Since when does he know how it feels to ride on wheels?
¿Desde cuándo sabe tanto de eso?
So? What do you want me to do here?
¿Entonces?
There he goes again!
¡Ahí va otra vez!
Nice. My gosh!
¡Vaya, genial!
Awesome. That was great.
Qué genial.
Amazing! He even did an ollie.
¡Increíble! Hasta hizo un ollie.
As you just saw, there's such a wide variety of skateboarding tricks.
Como ven, hay una gran variedad de trucos de patineta.
The person who can do all of the four tricks we just showed you
Quien pueda hacer los cuatro trucos que les mostramos
will unquestionably become the first-place winner.
se convertirá sin duda en el ganador.
Great.
Genial.
I should've just stayed home.
Debí quedarme en casa.
Why are there so many people here? It's annoying.
¿Por qué hay tanta gente? Qué molesto.
Best of luck. You got this.
Mucha suerte. Tú puedes.
You look so cool!
- Te ves bien. - ¿Qué es eso?
What's going on?
¿Qué pasa?
Here goes the first contestant.
Nuestra primera concursante rubia va bien por ahora.
Oh, no! Too bad. She's been disqualified.
¡Qué mal! Quedó descalificada.
The second contestant, please proceed.
Que pase el segundo concursante. ¡Vaya qué hábil!
My gosh, he's--
Cielos, está…
Oh, no.
¡No!
The third contestant, please come on out.
Que pase el tercero.
I think he'll be great.
Creo que le irá bien.
Oh, my! Amazing!
¡Vaya!
Just this once. Please? Just one time.
Hágalo solo esta vez. ¿Por favor? Solo una vez.
We don't know how long we might end up having to stay here.
No sabemos cuánto tiempo tendremos que estar aquí.
-He didn't make it. -Lord Habaek, please.
- No pudo. - Por favor, señor.
That's too bad. He was so close.
Qué lástima. Estuvo muy cerca.
The fifth contestant, please come on out.
¿Y el quinto concursante?
-Please, My Lord. -The fifth contestant?
- Por favor. - ¿El quinto?
Are you giving up?
¿Te rindes?
I get it. It must be extremely nerve-racking.
Te entiendo. Debe ser muy estresante.
-Who is it? -Why isn't he coming out?
¿Por qué no sale?
Will the one who can do all four tricks come in first place?
¿Ganaré si hago los cuatros trucos?
Be gentle. Please take it easy.
Tómelo con calma.
FIRST PLACE PRIZE: 100,000 WON
PRIMER LUGAR: 100 000 WONES
What must I do if I want to win all three prizes?
¿Y si quiero los tres premios?
-Pardon me? -You'll have to give me everything.
- ¿Qué? - Tendrás que darme todo.
Know that this is a huge honor.
- Será un honor para ustedes. - ¿Qué dijo?
-Excuse me, sir. -Goodness.
- Señor. - Dios mío.
You must be extremely nervous now.
Debe estar muy nervioso.
You're going the wrong way. You have to come here.
Debe partir por acá.
What?
¿Qué?
Lord Habaek, please be gentle.
Señor Habaek, tenga cuidado.
Please be careful. Gosh!
No se lastime.
Who is that man?
¿Quién es él?
Professional skateboarders can't participate.
Era sin profesionales.
That man you're looking at now
Hasta el día de hoy,
had never even seen a skateboard until today.
nunca había visto una patineta.
Don't you...
¿No sientes
feel like something in your heart...
que tu corazón
is smacking...
está intentando
your head?
decirte algo?
You came.
Viniste.
Yes, he is that guy.
Sí, es él.
Gosh, this is crazy. Why did I have to run into that guy here?
Qué locura. ¿Por qué tenía que estar ahí?
You, my servant over there!
¡Oye, sirvienta!
I'm here!
¡Aquí estoy!
My gosh, what's his problem? What is he doing?
Dios mío, ¿qué está haciendo?
Is he following me? Why? Why is he following me?
¿Me está siguiendo? ¿Por qué?
-Are you sure she's a descendant? -Yes.
- ¿En verdad es ella? - Sí.
What did I tell you? I said it'd wake her up.
Te dije que la despertaría.
Hang on a second.
Espera un poco.
-Why on earth am I running away? -Hey, servant!
- ¿Por qué estoy huyendo? - ¡Sirvienta!
Oh, right.
Cierto. Dijo que era como la naturaleza.
By the way, why is she running away?
¿Por qué está huyendo?
She's looking for me, not running away.
Me está buscando, no huyendo.
She is running away.
Está huyendo.
Hey, servant!
¡Oye, sirvienta!
You slow-witted woman! I'm right here!
¡Mujer necia, estoy aquí!
Gosh, what a psycho!
Cielos, está loco.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Goodness, this guy is blocking our way again.
Vaya, es el tipo que nos bloqueó el camino.
Move!
¡Muévete!
How impudent.
Qué insolente.
Gosh, this is so crazy.
Qué locura.
-Why did I-- -Servant!
- ¿Por qué me…? - ¡Sirvienta!
Why...
¿Por qué escapé si no hice nada malo?
This is all Sang-yu's fault.
Esto es culpa de Sang-yu.
Why did he tell me to exercise?
¿Por qué me dijo que hiciera ejercicio?
I shouldn't have to worry about diabetes. I'm a doctor.
Soy doctora, estoy bien de salud.
It got in the water. Find something we can use to get it out.
Se cayó. Busca algo para alcanzarla.
-Gosh, seriously! -I'll come with you.
Te ayudaré.
Please!
Por favor.
Please save me!
Sálvame, por favor.
Dad!
Papá.
I told you that humans are not trustworthy.
Te dije que los humanos no son confiables.
You want a prize?
¿Quieres el premio?
Had you wanted to scam me, you should've done it properly.
Si querías estafarme, debiste hacerlo bien.
Which professional team does he belong to? Seriously.
¿A qué equipo pertenece? En serio.
Why did you do that?
¿Por qué hizo eso?
I told you not to go overboard and to do it like a newbie.
Le dije que no se excediera y se lo tomara con calma.
You're so mean.
Es muy malo.
Had I had the kind of power that you have,
Si tuviera su poder,
I would have gladly used it for you.
lo hubiera usado con gusto por usted.
I feel the same way.
Pienso igual.
I wanted to win all the prizes and make you happy.
Quería ganar todos los premios y hacerte feliz.
Lord Habaek.
Señor Habaek.
My Lord...
Mi señor.
You didn't actually think I'd say such a thing, did you?
No creíste que hablaba en serio, ¿cierto?
Of course not.
No.
It clearly didn't wake her up.
No la despertó.
You should just give up.
Debería rendirse.
It'd be faster to appeal to her sympathy.
Sería más rápido pedirle ayuda.
The total site is 20,000 pyeong.
El área es de 20 000 pyeong.
According to our research, there are five landowners in total.
Y hay cinco dueños en total.
About 15,000 pyeong of the land can be purchased with no issues.
Podemos comprar 15 000 sin problemas.
Do we have the landowners' contact information?
- ¿Conocemos a los dueños? - Así es.
Well, but...
Pero…
Go ahead.
- Adelante. - Nos será difícil comprar
It's because...
Y eso se debe
that land belongs to Chairman Shin.
a que le pertenecen al presidente Shin.
It's not easy to persuade him.
No es alguien fácil de persuadir.
I'll take care of it.
Yo me encargo.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Of all, Chairman Shin's land...
Tenía que ser de él.
The selling price will jump up.
El precio de venta subirá.
Yes, Mr. Choi. Go ahead.
Sí, señor Choi. Dígame.
Sure. We'll be fine with that.
Por supuesto.
No. Please prepare the second car.
No. Por favor, prepare el segundo auto.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Apparently, it'll take some time for the windshield wiper to arrive.
Los limpiaparabrisas demorarán en llegar.
Sure.
Bien.
I can’t wait all day.
No puedo seguir esperando.
You've kept me waiting since this morning.
Llevo toda la mañana esperando.
I'm not asking for a new loan.
Solo estoy pidiendo una extensión.
Is it that hard to check it for me?
¿Es eso tan difícil?
What's the point of having a big car?
¿Por qué no lo usa?
My gosh, I'm so sorry.
Dios mío, lo siento mucho.
I don't think...
No creo que puedan pagar el costo de la reparación.
Why is it so expensive? It's just a windshield wiper.
¿Por qué es tan caro?
What? Rain sensors?
¿Qué? ¿Sensores de lluvia?
I get it.
Entiendo.
Hello.
Hola.
How was your trip to Gangwon Province?
¿Cómo estuvo tu viaje a Gangwon?
By the way, about the windshield wiper...
Por cierto, el limpiaparabrisas…
The cost of genuine parts and the labor...
El costo por el repuesto original…
I have a friend who works at a body shop.
Tengo un amigo que trabaja en un taller.
-He said if we don't use genuine-- -Do you think they'll understand?
- Si usamos alternativos… - ¿Crees que lo entenderán?
I think I'll have to move out.
Creo que tendré que mudarme.
Tell them we'll go through insurance.
- Diles que lo verá el seguro. - ¿Qué?
Don't be so down when you talk to them.
No te deprimas.
Have confidence and make it simple. Practice.
Ten confianza y sé directo. Práctica.
Sure. Go through insurance.
Claro. Lo verá el seguro.
All right.
Está bien.
Patient Ma Bong-yeol is going to be hospitalized today,
El paciente Ma Bong-yeol necesita una referencia para ser hospitalizado.
Also, Park Sang-cheol called again.
Y Park Sang-cheol dijo que llamaría más tarde.
Gosh.
Cielos.
How can you sleep for that long?
¿Cómo puedes dormir tanto?
I was tired.
Estaba cansado.
You might be fine because you're a pure deity,
Usted está bien porque es una deidad pura,
but I'm just an ordinary deity, and I get tired like humans.
pero yo soy una deidad ordinaria y me canso como los humanos.
I'm starving too.
Y tengo hambre.
-Is that something I must hear? -Sorry.
¿Debo escuchar eso?
Let's go.
Vamos.
Pardon me? To where?
¿Disculpe?
Home?
¿A casa?
Where...
¿Dónde…?
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH
SANTA SALUD MENTAL
What a coincidence.
Qué coincidencia.
If I'd have known that you had this in your hand,
De haber sabido que tenía esto, no hubiéramos tenido que ir a Gangwon.
But at least I'm smart enough
Al menos recordé que la señorita me había dado dinero
Otherwise, we'd be walking all day again.
o hubiéramos caminado todo el día.
But I wonder whether Ms. Descendant will be so generous.
Me pregunto si nos ayudará.
-Yes? -I'd like to try driving.
- Quiero intentar conducir. - ¿Qué?
-What? -I said I'll do it.
- Que quiero conducir. - ¿Qué está diciendo?
-Get out of my car now. -I'm sorry. Okay.
- Bájense. - Lo siento.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
Who came by?
¿Quién vino?
The agent of the landowner.
- El agente del dueño. - ¿Y por qué vino?
I thought they're taking the rent off the deposit.
¿No iba a sacar la renta del depósito?
It was something like an ultimatum.
Fue como un ultimátum.
He wants to raise the deposit by 50 million won.
Quiere aumentar el depósito.
What?
¿Qué?
That's him.
Ahí está.
Yes. We're almost there.
Sí, ya casi llegamos.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
He'd like to see you in an hour.
Lo quiere ver en una hora.
Chairman Shin won't look at the business proposal, as you said.
Tal como dijo, el presidente Shin no quiere ver la propuesta.
Sure, he won't.
Claro que no.
-I'll help you. -No, thank you.
- ¿Lo ayudo? - No, gracias.
-It's fine. I can handle myself. Go on. -Okay.
Puedo cuidarme solo, descuida.
It says it's across the street.
Dice que está en frente.
Oh, we have to cross too.
Debemos cruzar.
There she is.
Ahí está.
I told you. She has been awakened.
¿Ves? Te dije que la desperté.
Sir, I'll help you.
Señor, déjeme ayudarlo.
No, it's fine. Go on.
Estoy bien, descuida.
Isn't she the windshield doctor?
¿Es la doctora del limpiaparabrisas?
Her hospital must be near here.
Su clínica debe estar cerca.
Thank you.
Gracias.
I guess she saw something we didn't since she's a psychiatrist.
Como psiquiatra, quizá vio algo que nosotros ignoramos.
Maybe.
Tal vez.
She looks good in the doctor's gown.
La bata de doctor le queda bien.
I agree.
Estoy de acuerdo.
My goodness!
¡Dios mío!
How did you get here?
¿Cómo llegaste aquí?
I took what's called a taxi.
Tomé algo llamado "taxi".
It was more spacious than your car.
Era más espacioso que tu auto.
So now I only have half of the money you gave me.
Me queda solo la mitad del dinero que me diste.
Good to see you again.
Nos volvemos a ver.
Why did you just leave yesterday?
¿Por qué te fuiste ayer?
What?
- ¿Qué? - Si despertaste, debiste ir a saludarme.
Teach her etiquette first.
Enséñale modales.
I won't need your help so much.
No necesito tanta ayuda,
First, I need a house to stay,
solo un lugar donde quedarme, comida para Namsuri,
and a change of clothes.
un cambio de ropa y algo de ese llamado "dinero".
I heard it's better if you have more.
Oí que es mejor si tienes más.
I'll let you know if I need anything else.
Te avisaré si necesito algo más.
Also, there are gods I have to find.
Además, debo encontrar a otros dioses.
The coronation must take place immediately.
La coronación debe realizarse,
So try your best to find them as fast as you can.
así que encuéntralos pronto.
Do you have any questions?
¿Preguntas?
Let's talk.
Conversemos.
Sir, you shouldn't let him do what he wants.
No puedes dejar que haga lo que quiera.
Does he go to a hospital?
- ¿Va a algún hospital? - ¿Perdón?
No?
¿No?
Hey, look.
Escucha.
Mental illness is the same as physical illness.
Las enfermedades mentales son como las físicas.
Don't you go to a hospital when you're sick?
Debes llevarlo a un hospital.
Do you just endure the pain of your injuries until it gets better?
No puedes esperar a que se mejore solo.
Namsuri is very hungry.
Namsuri tiene mucha hambre.
And I need water.
Y yo necesito agua.
Then go home and take care of your problems.
Pues ve a casa y soluciónalo.
-Where is your house? -No.
- ¿Dónde vives? - No.
Not my house. Your house.
Ve a tu casa.
Sorry, but we don't have a place to go.
Lo siento, pero no tenemos dónde ir.
Please help us.
Ayúdanos, por favor.
Then you could go to the community service center
Podrías pedir ayuda en tu centro comunitario.
I don't know how good the welfare system is in this country,
No sé qué tan bueno es el sistema en este país,
but I think it is the country's duty
pero cuidar de personas como tú es deber del país.
It's not a personal problem.
No es mi problema.
Let's eat up.
A comer.
That's why we're paying taxes.
Para eso pagamos impuestos.
I can't afford to look after other people.
No puedo cuidar a otras personas.
Then why did you just walk with the old man?
¿Entonces por qué cruzaste la calle con el anciano?
When...
¿Cuándo hice eso?
I saw it. I saw it all.
Recién.
-I was just walking. -You were walking with him.
- Solo estaba caminando. - Junto a él.
I was only walking.
Solo estaba caminando.
You're not very honest.
No eres muy honesta.
That's got nothing to do with this. The country--
Eso no tiene que ver con esto. El país…
-I don't know what you're talking about. -I know.
- No sé de qué hablas. - Lo sé.
Anyway, if you ever show up here again,
Como sea, si vuelven a aparecer por aquí,
I'll report you to the police.
llamaré a la policía.
If you leave like this, I'll let you go.
Dejaré que te vayas,
That means I'll abandon you.
pero te abandonaré.
I'm very glad to hear that.
Me alegra escuchar eso.
See?
¿Ve?
It did not wake her.
No la despertó.
-What's up? -Did you meet Mr. Bang?
- ¿Sí? - ¿Viste al señor Bang?
No, not yet. Where's his office again? I should go there.
Aún no. ¿Dónde estaba su oficina?
It's not far, but you should get back here first.
No está lejos, pero debes regresar.
Mr. Ma Bong-yeol's guardian is here.
Vino el guardián del Sr. Ma Bong-yeol. Necesita tu firma.
Really? Okay, I'll be there shortly.
¿En serio? Bien, iré pronto.
You're in trouble. Do you know who he is?
- Estás en problemas. ¿Sabes quién es? - ¿Qué?
-What did you just say? -I didn't say anything.
- ¿Qué dijiste? - No dije nada.
You'll suffer to death.
Vas a sufrir.
Gosh, these people...
Cielos, esta gente. ¿Cómo te atreves a amenazarme?
Now we won't even be able to appeal to her sympathy.
Ahora no nos tendrá compasión.
I asked you to give me a heads-up before you do anything.
Le dije que me avisara si hacía algo.
We should take care of urgent business first.
Debemos solucionar nuestro problema.
I hate that we have to do this,
No quería hacer esto,
but we should go there.
pero deberíamos ir ahí.
Where?
¿A dónde?
The place I buried gold.
A donde enterré el oro.
-Gold? -I buried some gold
- ¿Oro? - Enterré oro cuando vine hace 55 años.
I didn't do it to prepare for a day like this.
No lo hice pensando en esto.
I didn't know it'd be this useful.
No sabía que sería útil.
With that gold, I'll be able to find a better place for you to stay.
Con ese oro, podré consegurinos un mejor lugar.
So...
Entonces,
you're saying that you made me go through all this trouble
¿me hiciste pasar por todo esto
when we had that option?
cuando teníamos esa opción?
I didn't want to go there because it has bad vibes.
El lugar tiene malas vibras, porque ahí se reúnen
Fugitives from the divine world gather there.
- los fugitivos del mundo divino. - ¿Dónde es?
-The pear tree field. -Pear tree field?
- En el campo de perales. - ¿Perales?
Pear tree field.
Campo de perales.
This used to be a field of pear trees.
Solía ser un campo de perales.
Gosh, this is not what I expected.
No me esperaba esto.
You say that all the time.
Dices eso todo el tiempo.
-Goodness. -I'm sorry.
- Cielos. - Lo siento.
Just deal with it.
Aguántate.
Here. Is that enough?
Ahí tienes. ¿Es suficiente?
You're one strange man.
Qué raro eres.
Are you really going to eat all this food?
¿En verdad comerás todo eso?
Hold on. You need to finish the job before you start eating.
Espera, debes terminar tu trabajo antes de comer.
What?
¿Qué?
Oh, right.
Cierto.
The blockage on the path from east to west will be removed,
El camino este-oeste se desbloqueará,
which means energy will rush in from both directions.
lo que hará que la energía fluya libremente.
Like a tiger that threatens all other creatures,
Como un tigre que acecha a su presa,
you have a triumphant and bright future ahead.
tendrás un futuro triunfante por delante.
You can expect great news around November this year.
Espera buenas noticias para noviembre.
Great news?
¿Buenas noticias?
Eat up.
Adelante.
What does hunger feel like?
¿Cómo es tener hambre?
How pathetic.
Qué patético.
It's just a feeling.
- Es solo una sensación. - Tiene razón.
You said losing your power doesn't mean you're no longer a god.
Sigue siendo un dios aunque no tenga poderes.
Since you still don't feel hunger,
Como aún no siente hambre, debe tener razón.
Did you just realize that now?
¿Acabas de darte cuenta?
Let's go.
Vamos.
Pardon? May I finish eating this?
¿Puedo terminar esto?
What should we do now?
¿Qué hacemos ahora?
It'd be best if we could find those deities,
Encontrar a los dioses sería útil, pero no sabemos cómo hacerlo.
Even if we decide to wait for your power to come back,
Aunque recupere sus poderes, no podemos seguir en la calle.
Plus, I'll continue to get hungry,
Además, debemos hallar una forma para alimentarme.
You're still Lord Habaek even without your power,
Sigue siendo el señor Habaek, pero esto es muy inconveniente.
Why do you think you lost your power?
¿Por qué habrá perdido sus poderes?
We should find Ms. Descendant again and ask her for--
Deberíamos buscar a la Srta. Descendiente y pedirle…
You're being such a nuisance. I can't take this anymore.
Qué molestia. Ya no aguanto más.
Pardon?
¿Perdón?
What did I do?
¿Qué hice?
Stop following me and reveal yourself already.
Deja de seguirme.
Why are you following me?
- ¿Por qué me sigues? - ¿Es usted el señor Habaek?
Who are you?
¿Quién eres?
It's me.
Soy yo.
He does look familiar.
Se ve familiar.
It's me, Jugeollin.
Soy yo, Jugeollin.
Don't you recognize me?
¿Me reconoce?
-I don't know you. -Jugeollin?
- No. - ¿Jugeollin?
There's no way you don't know me.
Es imposible que no me conozca.
You better know me.
Tiene que reconocerme.
-You-- -You little...
- Es… - ¡Maldito!
What on earth was that about?
¿Qué rayos fue eso?
You must've really lost all of your power.
Parece que en verdad perdiste tus poderes.
How...
¿Cómo puedes no reconocerme?
-Who are you? -I...
- ¿Quién eres? - He…
I've been desperately waiting for a day like this. You...
He esperado desesperadamente un día como este.
You're doomed now.
¡Estás en problemas ahora!
Who is that scum?
¿Quién es esa basura?
Lord Habaek.
Señor Habaek.
Are you all right?
¿Está bien?
Who is he?
- ¿Quién es? - Es Jugeollin, la deidad voraz.
He fled from the Land of Water because of you and Mura.
Huyó del Reino del Agua por usted y Mura.
Who?
¿Quién?
He kissed you.
Lo besó.
You'll be okay, right?
Estará bien, ¿cierto?
Yes, Mr. Bang.
Sí, señor Bang.
I'm one of your tenants at Daebak Building.
Soy la arrendataria de la clínica Santa Salud Mental.
Yes, that's right. Where are you now?
Así es. ¿Dónde está?
I'd like to meet with you.
Quisiera verlo.
Look who's here.
Miren quién llegó.
Where do you even come from?
¿Y tú de dónde saliste?
What brings you here?
¿Qué haces aquí?
Are you here to take more things from my family or what?
¿Viniste a robar más de mi familia?
-He's completely ignoring me. -Hello, sir.
- Me ignora por completo. - Hola, señor.
-Hey, my nephew is here. -He's not really your nephew.
Mi sobrino.
Just because he's our family on paper doesn't make him our family.
Que lo sea en papel no lo convierte en familia.
Be respectful, will you?
Sé más respetuosa, ¿quieres?
Respectful, my foot.
¿Respetuosa? Sí, claro.
Be quiet. Give me the car key.
Silencio. Dame las llaves.
Grandpa!
¡Abuelo!
You know how well people treat you because you own a few buildings.
Sabes que te tratan bien solo por tus propiedades.
Let me run my own talent agency.
Déjame abrir mi propia agencia de talentos.
Your car is over there, so just leave.
Ahí está tu auto, así que vete.
From the towing fee and the storage cost to the penalty...
Con el remolque y la multa…
You eat up so much money.
Me cuestas tanto dinero.
Grandpa, listen to me.
Abuelo, escúchame.
A celebrity like me shouldn't get a ticket for illegal parking
No deberían remolcarle el auto a una celebridad como yo.
Help me start a business!
¡Ayúdame con mi negocio!
Let's go.
Vamos.
Don't stay out late!
No salgas hasta tarde.
Grandpa, please. Grandpa!
Abuelo, por favor. ¡Abuelo!
Don't leave, Grandpa.
No te vayas.
Mr. Cha.
Señor Cha.
Why did you give my role in the romantic drama to a no-name actress?
¿Por qué le diste mi papel a una actriz desconocida?
Sir!
¡Señor!
Hello.
Hola.
-Is the tenant leaving today? -Yes.
- ¿El arrendatario se va hoy? - Sí.
Do a thorough check before they leave.
Revisa todo antes de que se vaya.
Make sure they don't leave any garbage in the property.
Que no deje nada de basura.
You know how expensive garbage bags are.
Esas bolsas son muy costosas.
Please don't worry, sir.
No se preocupe, señor.
That rude jerk.
Qué tipo más pesado.
He didn't even bother to say goodbye.
Ni siquiera se despidió.
Eighth floor.
Octavo piso.
I paid so much money for her medical school.
Pagué mucho dinero para que estudiara medicina.
If I had two grandchildren, I would've gotten rid of her already.
Si tuviera dos hijos, ya me habría deshecho de ella.
You won't believe how much I had to pay in taxes this month.
No creerías cuántos impuestos tuve que pagar este mes.
Those ruthless thieves.
Esos ladrones despiadados.
They've done nothing for me, but why are they taking so much money?
No hacen nada por mí, pero se llevan mi dinero.
So,
Entonces,
did you say that you're going to build a new resort?
¿quieres construir un centro turístico?
Yes, sir. I think I'll need a lot of your help.
Sí, señor. Creo que necesitaré su ayuda.
I'm just an old man. How will I be able to help you?
Solo soy un viejo. ¿Cómo podría ayudarte?
I vaguely heard about it from Mr. Min.
El señor Min me contó algo al respecto,
But it was so complicated that I really couldn't understand.
pero era tan complicado que no pude entender,
So let's just get to the point.
así que vayamos al grano.
How much will I be able to earn from this deal?
¿Cuánto podré ganar con este negocio?
I'm planning to pay five times the official price.
Puedo ofrecer cinco veces el precio.
Those countrymen will get to earn some money.
Esos campesinos podrán ganar algo de dinero.
How much will you give me then?
Entonces, ¿cuánto me darás a mí?
That's so immoral.
Eso es inmoral.
"Immoral"?
¿Inmoral?
You can't even afford to pay rent, so I'm taking the money from your deposit.
No pagas la renta, así que la saqué de tu depósito.
Don't you think you're the one who's being more immoral?
¿No crees que la inmoral eres tú?
I'm really sorry about that, and I'm also very grateful.
Lamento mucho eso y también estoy muy agradecida.
So please help me by convincing him not to raise the deposit.
Por favor, ayúdeme a que no suba el depósito.
Once my clinic settles down--
Cuando me vaya bien…
"That's exactly what I don't understand!
"¡Es que no lo entiendo!
Why are you trying to settle down in my building?"
¿Por qué quieres instalarte en mi edificio?".
That's exactly what the chairman will say,
Eso es lo que diría el presidente,
in my opinion.
en mi opinión.
"She should settle down in some other building!
"¡Deberías instalarte en otro edificio!
Why is she trying to settle down in my building?"
¿Por qué quieres hacerlo en el mío?".
That's what he'll say as he scolds me.
Eso es lo que dirá cuando me regañe.
Okay, then. I'll talk to him myself.
Está bien, hablaré yo misma con él.
No, you can't do that!
¡No puedes hacer eso!
The chairman is not available right now.
El presidente no está disponible ahora.
I'll pay six times the original price for your land.
Le ofrezco seis veces el precio.
You're paying five times the original price to those
Le ofreciste cinco veces el precio original
who you're not even acquainted with.
a gente que no conoces.
Don't you think you're being cheap towards your family?
Estás siendo avaro con tu familia.
I won't be too greedy.
No seas codicioso.
Just pay me... ten times the original price.
Mejor ofréceme
I'm sure you have your reputation to think about at work,
Seguro debes cuidar tu reputación,
so I, your uncle, will help you save face.
así que tu tío te ayudará con eso.
By the way, are you trying to build an amusement park or something?
Por cierto, ¿quieres construir un parque de diversiones o algo así?
I heard restaurants earn a lot of money in amusement parks.
Oí que los restaurantes ganan mucho dinero ahí.
It'll be open bidding.
Será una licitación abierta.
If you're interested, you should get ready to participate.
Si le interesa, debe participar.
Why are you making things so complicated?
¿Por qué complicas tanto las cosas?
You can just add another article in my contract.
Puedes agregar otro artículo en mi contrato.
I'm willing to give you my precious land.
Te daré mi preciado terreno,
Just cut me some slack and make it easy for me.
ten algo de consideración.
I can't do that, sir.
No puedo hacer eso, señor.
Who is it?
¿Quién es?
Who are you?
¿Quién eres?
The third floor...
Soy…
What?
¿Qué?
I'm a tenant on the third floor of Daebak Building.
Soy la arrendataria de la clínica psiquiátrica.
Oh, yes. That mental hospital.
Sí, cierto. ¿El manicomio?
It's not exactly a mental hospital.
No es un manicomio.
You suddenly doubled the deposit, so I came here to talk about that.
Vine a hablar sobre el alza del depósito.
That's great. I've been meaning to meet you anyway. I'm glad you came.
Ya quería hablar contigo. Me alegra que vinieras.
Why are you always so late in paying your monthly rent?
¿Por qué tardas tanto en pagar tu renta?
You have no common sense.
No tienes sentido común. Deberías saberlo.
Why are you causing a huge loss on someone else's property?
¿Por qué le causas pérdidas a las propiedades ajenas?
I barely manage to live day to day with your monthly rent.
Apenas tengo para vivir con tu renta mensual.
Are you trying to starve me to death?
¿Quieres matarme de hambre?
You have a guest with you, so I'll just come back next time.
Veo que está ocupado. Volveré en otra ocasión.
There's no need.
No es necesario.
You can stay if you have money. If not, please move out.
Si no tienes dinero, puedes mudarte.
I'm not so smart, so I hate complicated things.
No soy muy listo. Odio las cosas complicadas.
Young people these days only seem to blame others.
Los jóvenes de hoy le echan la culpa a los demás.
My gosh, why did he have to be there again?
¿Por qué me lo tenía que topar de nuevo?
You now belong to the gods.
Ahora me perteneces.
Accept your fate, or you'll go through everything.
Acepta tu destino o sufrirás.
This can't be...
¿Será esto
the "everything" that I'll be going through, can it?
el sufrimiento al que se refería?
Why am I thinking of such weird things?
¿Por qué estoy pensando en esa tontería?
Please give me water. I'm really thirsty.
Dame agua, por favor. Tengo mucha sed.
Can't you hear me? Please give me water.
¿Me oyes? Dame agua, por favor.
Are you trying to make me go dry?
¿Quieres que me seque?
My gosh.
Cielos.
Why did she have to be in my way? How stupid.
¿Por qué está estorbando ahí? Qué tonta.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
Doors closing. Basement one.
Cierre de puertas. Nivel uno del sótano.
First floor. Doors opening.
Primer piso. Abriendo puertas.
You should go back to the bank again and ask them for a loan.
Debería pedir el préstamo de nuevo.
Why are you always so nosy? You should mind your own business.
¿Por qué siempre se entromete? Ocúpese de sus asuntos.
You don't seem to mind your own business either.
Pareciera que no sigue su consejo.
-What did you say? -I saw you
- ¿Qué dijo? - La vi hace poco.
putting on a very awkward act at the crosswalk earlier.
Fingió no ayudar al anciano a cruzar la calle.
-I was just walking. -You were walking with him.
- Solo estaba caminando. - Junto a él.
-You're not very honest.
- No es cierto. - Oculta algo.
What is their problem?
¿Cuál es su problema?
-I wasn't criticizing you. -I didn't say you were.
- No la estoy criticando. - No dije que lo hiciera.
-About that windshield wiper-- -I'll handle it
- Y sobre el limpiaparabrisas… - Lo verá la aseguradora.
I was just about to tell you that you don't need to pay for it.
Iba a decir que no tiene que pagarlo.
Should I just mind my own business?
¿Me ocupo de mis asuntos?
Well...
Bueno, sí. Así es.
I see.
Ya veo.
Then I'd like you to pay the price.
Entonces páguelo.
Are you the guardian of Ma Bong-yeol?
¿Es el guardián de Ma Bong-yeol?
What? He ran away?
¿Qué? ¿Se escapó?
You're not very honest.
- Ocultas algo. - Oculta algo.
Why do you care?
¿Por qué les importa?
What?
¿Aló?
-What? -He ran away
¿Qué?
Why did you let him get away?
¿Por qué dejaste que se escapara?
What?
¿Qué? ¿Por qué debo buscarlo yo?
I'm not in good condition either.
Tampoco puedo.
I keep hearing weird things. I should get some rest.
Estoy escuchando cosas raras. Debo descansar.
It has nothing to do with our hospital anymore.
Ya no es nuestro paciente.
They'll take care of it now.
Que se encargue alguien más.
Forget that and call the police.
Olvídalo y llama a la policía. Y pregúntales si atraparon al ladrón.
Are you looking at what that kid's eating right now?
¿Está mirando lo que el chico está comiendo?
-No. -Then what are you looking at?
No.
I'm not looking at anything.
- No estoy mirando nada. - ¿Quiere?
Take that away.
Aleja eso.
Please let me know if you feel dizzy,
Avíseme si se siente mareado o débil.
That's how it feels when you're hungry.
Eso pasa con el hambre.
Eating this will help you feel better.
Comer lo hará sentir mejor.
I guess if you lose your power, spells of the lower deities work on you.
Parece que Jugeollin le echó un maleficio.
Why aren't we using a taxi?
¿Por qué no estamos en un taxi?
We need to save up. We both need to eat to survive now.
Nos queda solo esto para sobrevivir.
I had no idea Jugeollin would be here.
No sabía que Jugeollin estaría aquí.
When exactly was it
¿Cuándo fue que lo desafió y le dejó esa cicatriz…?
He didn't leave that scar.
Él no me dejó la cicatriz.
He accidentally dropped his knife as he was so nervous.
Se le cayó la espada por los nervios, luego rebotó en una rama y…
It doesn't matter.
No importa.
I heard he ran away after Mura threatened to kill him.
Oí que huyó cuando Mura amenazó con matarlo.
But I didn't know he'd be here.
Y ahora está acá.
I didn't know the human world would be so full of trash.
No sabía que el mundo humano tendría tanta basura.
Why do you think Jugeollin asked you to fight him?
¿Por qué lo habrá desafiado?
He must've been out of his mind.
Debió estar loco.
This is not good.
Esto no es bueno. Ahora hasta sentirá hambre.
Why are things getting so complicated?
¿Por qué nos pasa esto?
INCOMING CALL: SEUL-KI
LLAMADA ENTRANTE
Hey, I'm almost there.
Sí, ya casi llego.
I'm getting off now. Okay.
Me bajaré ahora.
Mura?
¿Mura?
-Lord Habaek! -Doors closing.
- ¡Señor Habaek! - Cierre de puertas.
Lord Habaek!
¡Señor Habaek!
-Lord Habaek! -Namsuri.
- Señor. - Namsuri.
Lord Habaek!
¡Señor Habaek!
Oh, no. What am I going to do?
¡No! ¿Qué voy a hacer?
He apparently found a way to contact aliens.
Encontró a un alienígena.
He uploaded a selfie on his social media account.
Acaba de publicar una selfi.
Hey, you're not supposed to look into a patient's private life.
No te metas en la vida privada de los pacientes.
I didn't have a choice because he threatened that
Dijo que si no lo seguía, se iría a otra clínica.
I think he's at a subway station right now.
Está en una estación de metro.
It looks like he's in Gangseo-gu by looking at the background.
Por el fondo, parece que está en Gangseo-gu.
Gosh, I feel like I know this place.
Creo que lo reconozco.
It says the next stop is Seonyudo Park.
La siguiente parada es el parque Seonyudo.
That means he's near the Han River.
- ¿Estará por el río Han? - Pero qué gran detective.
But what's this?
¿Qué significa esto?
He wrote that he has finally met a god.
Escribió que al fin conoció a un dios.
I'm so sick of this nonsense about gods.
Estoy harta de los dioses.
I'm the one who wants to meet a god.
Yo soy la que necesita conocer a un dios.
My mother told me that humans need to eat rice to gain energy.
Mamá decía que comer arroz te daba energía.
But I gained energy by eating chicken and pizza.
Pero yo la obtenía comiendo pollo y pizza.
Of course, that's only after my mother passed away.
Aunque empecé a hacerlo solo después de que ella muriera.
Here.
Veamos.
Don't refuse and eat up.
Con confianza.
The eldest should always get the drumstick.
El mayor siempre recibe el muslo.
-Here. -What are you doing?
- Tome. - ¿Qué haces?
Gosh, I'm sorry.
Cielos, lo siento.
People will believe me now that I have a photo to show them as evidence.
Ahora sí me creerán,
Oh, right. How's TF 1004 doing?
Por cierto, ¿cómo va el TF 1004?
I haven't been able to meet Obama yet.
Aún no he podido ver a Obama.
I'm doing my best.
Me estoy esforzando,
But I'm sorry to have disappointed you.
pero lamento decepcionarlo.
It wasn't like I had to save the world or anything.
Ni siquiera debía salvar al mundo, solo llamar a Obama.
But I even failed to do such a simple task.
Pero no pude hacer ni eso.
If Obama finds out about this...
Si Obama se entera de esto…
Who in the world is Obama?
¿Quién es Obama?
Pardon?
¿Qué?
He's not here.
No está aquí.
I even went to the station office.
Hasta los trabajadores dijeron que no vieron nada raro.
Are you happy now? You can close the hospital a little early today.
¿Estás contento?
I'm so tired. I need to go home and take a rest.
Estoy agotada. Necesito descansar.
He just uploaded something new on his Instagram.
Subió algo nuevo a su Instagram.
-Hey! -I think he's at Hangang Park.
- ¡Oye! - Está en el parque Hangang.
-I'll send it to you right away. -Don't send me anything.
Te lo envío ahora.
My gosh, this punk!
Diablos, ese idiota.
NURSE YU: PHOTO
ENFERMERO YU: FOTO
My gosh, I told him not to send me anything.
Le dije que no me enviara nada.
-Nurse Yu. -Did you know
- ¡Oye! - ¿Sabías que el Sr. Ma
that Mr. Ma tried to commit suicide
intentó suicidarse mientras estaba en otro hospital?
What?
¿Qué?
That's why his family hesitated in hospitalizing him.
Por eso su familia no quería hospitalizarlo.
But...
Pero…
Why are they telling us that now?
…¿por qué nos dicen eso ahora?
It must've been hard for the family to talk about it. What should we do?
Es un tema difícil. ¿Qué hacemos?
Call the police and ask them to find him.
Que lo busque la policía.
He hates the police and firemen.
Odia a la policía y a los bomberos.
So you should...
Deberías ir tú.
Nurse Yu!
¡Enfermero Yu!
Yes?
¿Sí?
Call the police and wash your hands of this matter.
Llama a la policía y olvídate del asunto.
Do you understand?
¿Entendido?
Why is everyone giving me a hard time?
¿Por qué me dificultan la vida?
I'm not going to live like them.
No viviré así.
NURSE YU
ENFERMERO YU
What are you doing, and where are you?
¿Qué está haciendo y dónde está?
I called the management office of Hangang Park.
Llamé al parque Hangang.
It's not too far from there.
No está tan lejos.
My gosh, is he doing this for fun?
Cielos, ¿está disfrutando esto?
-What? Obama? -Yes.
- ¿Qué quién es Obama? - Sí.
Who is Obama? Why do you keep talking about him?
Sigues mencionando a Obama. ¿Quién es?
Well, Obama was the 44th president of the United States.
Fue el 44.º presidente de Estados Unidos.
He first ran for the presidency in 2008 as a Democrat.
Fue el candidato demócrata el 2008.
I don't get what you're saying.
No entiendo lo que dices.
Pardon?
¿Perdón?
But I know for sure that Obama can't save the world.
Pero sé que Obama no puede salvar al mundo.
What?
¿Qué?
My gosh, why does it have to be the Han River of all places?
Cielos, ¿por qué tenía que ser aquí?
My goodness. I don't know why I have to do this.
¿Por qué tengo que hacer esto?
Why can't he save the world?
¿Por qué no puede?
My gosh, it's true.
- Vaya, era cierto. - ¿No es obvio?
It really is that guy.
En verdad era él.
-Then... -Why is he there?
¿Por qué está aquí?
Then who can save the world?
¿Y quién salvará al mundo?
How am I supposed to know that?
¿Cómo podría saber eso?
But I wouldn't have told you even if I did know
Aunque lo supiera, no te lo diría
because I'm not interested in humans.
porque no me interesan los humanos.
My gosh!
Dios mío.
Then why did TF 1004 call me and--
Entonces, ¿por qué me llamó TF 1004 y…?
Because he doesn't exist.
Porque no existe.
What do you mean?
- ¿Qué? - No hay nadie con ese nombre
with that kind of name
en ninguna de las tres naciones de los dioses.
He doesn't exist.
No existe.
Don't lie to me!
¡No me mientas!
He shouldn't get too angry.
No debería enojarse.
Stop lying to me, you swindler!
¡Deja de mentirme, estafador!
Listen to me carefully, you worthless human.
Escúchame bien, humano inútil.
I am the next king of the Land of Water
Soy el próximo rey del Reino del Agua y emperador de los dioses.
I am Habaek, the God of Water.
Soy Habaek, el dios del Agua.
But if you really are a god, you should know who can save the world.
Si realmente eres un dios, deberías saber quién salvará al mundo.
If it's not Obama, then who is it?
Si no es Obama, ¿quién?
Listen to me carefully, you worthless human.
Escúchame bien, humano inútil.
It takes just one person to ruin the world,
Solo hace falta una persona para arruinar el mundo,
but it takes more than one person to save the world.
pero se necesita más de una para salvarlo.
So...
Por lo tanto,
it's not something Obama can do by himself.
no es algo que Obama pueda hacer solo.
But...
Pero…
You should just focus on doing your best in life.
Deberías enfocarte en vivir de la mejor forma posible.
Don't waste time wandering around like this.
No pierdas el tiempo en esto.
My gosh, that fool.
Dios mío, ese tonto.
What more can I do?
¿Qué más puedo hacer?
What more can I do right now?
¿Qué más puedo hacer ahora?
Regardless of how much I try, I still can't reach the sky.
Aunque lo intente, no puedo alcanzar el cielo.
What more can I do?
¿Qué más puedo hacer?
I...
No puedo…
I can't touch the sky.
No puedo tocar el cielo.
Mr. Ma Bong-yeol.
Sr. Ma.
What...
¿Qué hace aquí?
Mr. Ma,
Puede hablar conmigo.
Talk to you about what? You don't even listen to what I say!
¿Sobre qué?
About your story.
Sobre su historia.
The story that you've always wanted to tell me.
La que siempre quiso contarme.
I know that you wanted to show your father
Sé que quería mostrarle a su padre
that you could reach the sky.
que podía alcanzar el cielo.
That's why you tried hard to meet Obama. Let's talk about that story.
Por eso quiso conocer a Obama. Hablemos de eso.
I already told you.
Ya se lo dije.
I already told you everything,
Ya le conté todo, pero ¡me ignoró!
She tends to do that.
Ella suele hacer eso.
-Mr. Ma, I-- -Don't come near me.
Sr. Ma…
I don't want to talk to you.
- No quiero hablar con usted. - Pero…
Humans are so loud.
Los humanos son tan ruidosos.
I should throw this away...
Debería tirar esto,
-no matter what. -No. I don't need your help.
- pase lo que pase. - No necesito su ayuda.
I'm going to meet TF 1004.
Conoceré a TF 1004.
He's the only person who actually understands me.
Es la única persona que me entiende.
Wait. Mr. Ma!
¡Espere, Sr. Ma!
Stop right there!
¡Deténgase!
Mr. Ma...
Sr. Ma…
Should I keep this and give it to Namsuri?
¿O se lo guardo a Namsuri?
Please...
Por favor,
Please stop him right now.
haz que se detenga.
How dare a servant tell me what to do?
¿Cómo se atreve una sirvienta a darme órdenes?
You do it.
Hazlo tú.
Mr. Ma.
Señor Ma.
Please come here. I'm sorry.
Venga aquí, por favor. Lo siento.
You were always like that while treating me.
Siempre me trataba así.
"Yes, I see. So?
"Sí, ya veo. ¿Y qué más?
I understand."
Sí, ya entiendo".
What do you even understand?
Ni siquiera me entiende.
Even now,
Incluso ahora,
you act like you care for me, but you have no intention of helping me.
actúa como si le importara, pero no quiere ayudarme.
I'm sure you never even thought about...
Seguro nunca se interesó
helping me while you sat behind that desk of yours.
en ayudarme mientras iba a su clínica.
No.
No.
I...
Yo…
14 YEARS AGO
HACE 14 AÑOS
Dad.
Papá.
Please.
Por favor.
The person you are calling cannot answer your call.
El destinatario no puede contestar su llamada.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Por favor deje su mensaje.
I'm going to make you regret this for the rest of your life.
Haré que te arrepientas de esto.
UNDYING CONNECTION BETWEEN PARENTS AND CHILDREN
LAZO ETERNO ENTRE PADRES E HIJOS
Please. Please save me.
Por favor.
Help me!
Ayúdame.
Please.
Por favor.
Please help me!
Ayúdame, por favor.
Dad!
Papá.
I regretted it.
Me arrepentí.
It was cold, dark,
Todo era frío, oscuro,
lonely, and scary.
solitario y aterrador.
But no one was there to help me.
Y no había nadie que me ayudara.
What are you doing? I said I'm going to die right now!
¿Qué hace? ¡Dije que me voy a matar!
Do you think I'm lying?
¿Cree que estoy mintiendo?
Are you mocking me? Do you think I won't be able to do it?
¿Se burla de mí? ¿Cree que no seré capaz?
Fine, I hope you all live a great life.
Bien, que tengan una buena vida.
I hate this filthy world!
¡Odio este maldito mundo!
No, no! Mr. Ma, stop!
¡No, señor Ma! ¡Deténgase!
-Help! -No.
- ¡Ayuda! - No.
No!
No.
-Help! -No.
- ¡Ayuda! - No.
Mr. Ma!
Señor Ma.
Dr. Yun, help!
¡Doctora Yun, auxilio!
Please.
Por favor.
Please save me!
Por favor, sálvame.
Dad!
Papá.
No, please...
No, por favor…
No. No!
No.
Help!
¡Ayuda!
No!
¡No!
You're one reckless woman.
Eres una mujer muy imprudente.
Hold this.
Sostén esto.
You guys are so loud.
Son demasiado ruidosos.
I want all of you to leave my house.
Quiero que se vayan de mi casa.
I didn't want to go in because it's so dirty.
No quería ir porque el agua está sucia.
No!
¡No!
My gosh, no! Please come out.
¡Dios mío, no! Por favor, regresa.
Get out of the water!
Sal del agua.
Please get out of the water. Please.
Sal del agua. Por favor.
Gosh, I'm sorry.
Dios, lo siento.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I apologize for everything.
Perdón por todo.
I told you to be quiet.
Te dije que guardaras silencio.
My gosh. Mr. Ma!
Dios mío, señor Ma.
Mr. Ma. Please...
Señor Ma, por favor.
Stop it!
¡Basta!
My lips belong to TF 1004.
Mis labios le pertenecen a TF 1004.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
And thank you.
Y gracias.
I'm glad you're thankful.
Me alegra escuchar eso.
Take that fool away from here.
Llévate a ese tonto.
Hey!
¡Oye!
I told you to hold this!
¡Te dije que lo sostuvieras!
It's not...
No es porque me lo quiera comer.
I was just saving it for Namsuri.
Lo estaba guardando para Namsuri.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Fate.
El destino.
It must be fate.
Debe ser el destino.
Are you really a god?
¿En verdad eres un dios?
Habaek is here.
- Habaek está aquí. - He estado pensando en ti.
Shut up.
Cállate.
Nothing could get you off my mind.
No podía sacarte de mi cabeza.
I must be going crazy.
Estoy enloqueciendo.
Look who's here. A beggar.
Miren quién llegó. La mendiga.
Why are you following my woman around and bothering her?
¿Por qué sigues y molestas a mi mujer?
Were you playing the knight in shining armor?
¿Jugabas a ser caballero?
I keep running into this girl, Yun So-a.
Sigo topándome con ella.
Shall we switch over to a mystery, thriller, and suspense movie?
¿Cambiamos al género de misterio o de suspenso?
You and I are accomplices with regard to the sacred stone.
Tú y yo somos cómplices por las piedras sagradas.
Were you toying with me? You foolish human.
¿Estabas jugando conmigo? Mujer necia.
Don't you dare test me.
No te atrevas a ponerme a prueba.
EPILOGUE
EPÍLOGO
-High Priest. -Gosh, you brat.
-Alto sacerdote. - Cielos, mocosa.
Wait, High Priest.
Espere, sumo sacerdote.
High Priest.
Sumo sacerdote.
What is fate? Please tell me.
¿Qué es el destino? Por favor, dígame.
-I won't tell you. -High Priest, please.
- No te lo diré. - Sumo sacerdote, por favor.
High Priest, what is fate? Please tell me.
Sumo sacerdote, ¿qué es el destino? Dígame.
Disclosing the profound secret.
Es un secreto de la naturaleza.